eurotunnel.com 2019-07-12

# Privacy and Cookies – Eurotunnel Le Shuttle

## What does this notice cover?

The Privacy Notice describes how Eurotunnel, which is the trading name of the partnership between the Channel Tunnel Group Limited and France Manche SA, and part of the Getlink group of companies (“ **Eurotunne** l”, “ **we** ” or “ **us** ”), uses your personal data.

It also describes your data protection rights, including a right to object to some of the processing which Eurotunnel carries out. More information about your rights, and how to exercise them, is set out in the “What are your rights and choices?” section below.

We may also provide you with additional information when we collect personal data, where we feel it would be helpful to provide relevant and timely information.

## What personal data does Eurotunnel collect?

We collect and process personal data when you interact with us. This includes:

  * Your name, username and password.
  * Your gender, age and date of birth.
  * Contact details, such as your home address and postcode, email address and phone number.
  * Advance Passenger Information for you and your fellow travellers such as your nationality, national identification document (e.g. passport) and document number, and the issuing state of that document.
  * Recordings of your telephone calls to our contact centre.
  * CCTV images and recordings.
  * Where you, or your fellow passengers, are wheelchair users.
  * The registration details of your vehicle, including through the use of Automatic Number Plate Recognition technology.
  * Encrypted debit or credit card details, where you make purchases from us.
  * Your marketing preferences, your interests (including your holiday, travel, food, drink and entertainment preferences), your preferred language, images and video from social media and any consents you have given us.
  * Information about your health if you purchase travel insurance.
  * Information related to the browser or device you use to access our website, your IP address and cookie preferences.

## What personal data does Eurotunnel receive from third parties?

Our trusted suppliers provide anonymised web analytics and reporting services, user behaviour analytics, account analysis and profiling services. We share anonymised customer data with them for these purposes. Other trusted suppliers send us the information you submit to them if you respond to marketing messages, surveys or competitions or send us images or video.  We receive confirmation of payment and encrypted debit or credit card details for booking validation and fraud prevention purposes.

## How does Eurotunnel use your personal data and what is the legal basis for its use?

We use the personal data referred to above for the following purposes:

**Where necessary to fulfil a contract, or take steps linked to a contract. This is relevant where you purchase tickets from us, purchase other products and services or enter a competition we run. This includes:**

  * Taking payments and validating bookings.
  * Communicating with you.
  * Providing customer service and arranging the delivery or other provision of products, services or prizes.

**Where necessary for Eurotunnel’s legitimate interests, as listed below, and where our interests are not overridden by your data protection rights:**

  * Using your information to provide products and services you have requested and to respond to any comments or complaints you may send us.
  * Monitoring the use of our websites, and using personal data to help us improve and protect our services and websites, both online and offline.
  * Using information you provide to personalise our website, products or services for you.
  * If you provide a credit or debit card as payment, we use third parties to check the validity of the sort code, account number and card number you submit in order to prevent fraud.
  * We monitor customer accounts to prevent, investigate and/or report fraud, terrorism, misrepresentation, security incidents or crime, in accordance with applicable law.
  * To protect our legal rights and manage the security of our networks and property, (for example, through the use of CCTV).
  * We will use data in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory and investigative purposes as necessary (including disclosure of such information in connection with legal process or litigation).

**Where you give us consent:**

  * We will send you direct marketing in relation to our products and services, or other products and services provided by us, our affiliates and carefully selected partners.
  * We place cookies and use similar technologies in accordance with our Cookies Policy and the information provided to you when those technologies are used.
  * On other occasions when we ask you for consent, we will use the data for the purpose which we explain at the time.

**For purposes which are required by law:**

  * In response to requests from government law enforcement authorities conducting an investigation.
  * For national security, immigration and customs control purposes.

## How do we justify our legitimate interests?

We have carried out balancing tests for all the data processing we carry out on the basis of our legitimate interests, which we have described above. You can obtain information on our balancing tests by contacting us on the details below.

The provision of some information, such as the details you provide so we can send you marketing communications, is optional. However, in certain circumstances we will not be able to provide the services and/or products you have requested if we are not provided with all relevant personal data.

## How long will Eurotunnel keep your personal data?

Where we process your personal data in connection with the provision of our services, we keep the data for 6 years after you travel with us (except for your IP address which we keep for 2 years).

Where we process your personal data for marketing purposes or with your consent, we process the data for 3 years after you travel with us or until you ask us to stop and for a short period after this (to allow us to implement your requests). We also keep a record of the fact that you have asked us not to send you direct marketing or to process your data indefinitely so that we can respect your request in future.

We maintain administrative and financial records and make backup archive tapes of our IT systems on a monthly basis for disaster recovery management, information security and business management purposes. We retain this data for 15 years.

Recordings of your telephone calls to our contact centre are kept for 7 years in accordance with the requirements of the Financial Conduct Authority.

Images provided by you (for example Instagram images and videos) for use on our social media feed are kept until you ask us to delete them.   

CCTV images and recordings are retained for 30 days except where government authorities or law enforcement officials require footage to be preserved, in which case it is retained as long as is legally necessary.

Your IP address is retained in accordance with your cookie preferences.

## How will Eurotunnel share your personal data?

We will share your personal data with other members of the Getlink Group to administer and manage group functions, including the provision of our services and products to you.

Your personal data will also be shared with trusted third parties, such as our professional advisers and auditors, insurers, investment management, banks and other organisations which advise us.

If you purchase motor breakdown roadside assistance or personal travel insurance from us we will share your personal information with the companies though which we provide those services.  We do this in accordance with the requirements of the Financial Conduct Authority.  If you agree to receive marketing communications from us, participate in lifestyle, preference or customer satisfaction surveys or enter a competition, we share your personal data with the companies who provide these services with us or on our behalf.

Your personal data will also be shared with government authorities and/or law enforcement officials if required for the purposes above, if mandated by law or if required for the legal protection of our legitimate interests in compliance with applicable laws.

In the event that Eurotunnel is sold or integrated with another business, your details will be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchaser’s adviser and will be passed to the new owners of the business.

Your personal data is processed within the European Economic Area ("EEA").  If we share your personal data with third party service providers outside the EEA we will identify the vendors and the non-EEA countries in which they are located here: None.

Where information is transferred outside the EEA, and where this is to a stakeholder or vendor in a country that is not subject to an adequacy decision by the EU Commission, data is adequately protected by EU Commission approved standard contractual clauses, an appropriate Privacy Shield certification or a vendor's Processor Binding Corporate Rules.

If you live outside of the EEA, we will need to transfer your personal data outside of the EEA to respond to any queries that you may have. Where this applies, we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

For further information, including to obtain a copy of the documents used to protect your personal data, please contact us using the details set out below.

## What are your choices and rights?

The accuracy of the information that we hold about you is important to us. If any of the information that we hold is inaccurate or out of date, please let us know using the contact details set out at the end of this Privacy Notice. You also have the right:

  * To ask Eurotunnel for a copy of your personal data.
  * To have your personal data corrected if it is inaccurate or incomplete.
  * To have your personal data deleted.
  * To restrict the processing of your personal data.
  * To obtain the personal data you provide in a structured, machine readable format and ask us to share (port) this personal data to other organisations.
  * To object to processing in some circumstances.

Where we have asked for your consent, you may withdraw consent at any time. If you ask to withdraw your consent to Eurotunnel processing your personal data, this will not affect any processing which has already taken place at that time. You can also ask us not to send or to carry out profiling for direct marketing, at any time.

These rights may be limited in some situations – for example, where we can demonstrate that we have a legal requirement to process your data.

If you wish to exercise these rights, please contact us using the details below.

If you have unresolved concerns you have the right to complain to an EU data protection authority where you live, work or where you believe a breach may have occurred.   

## Updates to this notice

We keep our Privacy Notice under regular review, and may update it periodically. We will update the date at the top of this Privacy Notice accordingly. On some occasions, we may also actively advise you of specific data handling activities or significant changes to this Privacy Notice as required by applicable law. 

## Contact us

We hope that we can satisfy queries you may have about the way we process your data. If you have any concerns about how we process your data, feel free to discuss these with our legal department or the Getlink group Data Protection Officer, who can be contacted as follows:

## Eurotunnel Legal Department:

Email: [legal@eurotunnel.com](mailto:legal@eurotunnel.com)

Post: Eurotunnel Legal Department, UK Terminal, Ashford Road, Folkestone, Kent CT18 8XX  
Post: In France: Eurotunnel Department Juridique Siege Exploitation B.P. 69 62904 Coquelles. Cedex. France

## Getlink group Data Protection Officer

Email: [DPO@getlinkgroup.com](mailto:DPO@getlinkgroup.com)

By post in the UK: Eurotunnel Data Protection Officer, UK Terminal, Ashford Road, Folkestone, Kent CT18 8XX  
By post in France: Eurotunnel Data Protection Officer, Siege Exploitation B.P. 69 62904 Coquelles. Cedex. France

## Who is my data controller?

You data controller will be the Eurotunnel entity with which you have a relationship.

**In the UK** , this will be the Channel Tunnel Group Limited, which you can contact at:

Email: [legal@eurotunnel.com](mailto:legal@eurotunnel.com)  
Post: Legal Department Eurotunnel UK Terminal, Ashford Road, Folkestone, Kent CT18 8XX

**In France** , this will be France Manche SA, which you can contact at:

Email: [legal@eurotunnel.com](mailto:legal@eurotunnel.com)  
Post: Department Juridique Eurotunnel Siege Exploitation, B.P. 69 62904 Coquelles. Cedex. France
